barclayswealth.com 2013-03-27

# Privacy Policy - Barclays

>

##  Privacy Policy 

Please read our Privacy Policy carefully before using this website ("the Site"). In this Policy "we", "us" and "our" means Barclays Bank PLC and "you" means the individual who is using the Site. By using our Site, you agree with the collection, the use and the disclosure of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

We may change the content or services found on the Site at any time without notice, and consequently our Privacy Policy may change at any time in the future. Your continued access to or use of the Site will mean that you agree to the policy that applies when you use the site. 

Our Privacy Policy, together with the Important Information sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the "Act"), the data controller is Barclays Bank PLC. For the purposes of the Act, any member of the Barclays Group (defined below) may be our nominated representative. 

This policy contains the following sub-headings: 

  * Cookies
  * How we will use the information we collect about you?
  * Will we share your information with anyone else?
  * How long will we keep your personal information on file?
  * Electronic communications
  * Intellectual Property
  * Security
  * Calls

###  Cookies 

**What is a cookie?**

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information, which your computer or mobile device downloads when you visit a website. When you return to these websites – or visit other websites that use the same cookies – they recognise these cookies and therefore your browsing device.  
Cookies help websites to do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences and generally improving your browsing experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests. 

**What types of cookies do we use?**

The type of cookies used on this website can be put into one of four categories based on the International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) guide for cookie categories: Strictly Necessary, Performance, Functionality and Targeting. 

**Strictly Necessary Cookies** – These cookies are essential in order to enable you to navigate our websites and to access secure content. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, such as internet banking facilities, cannot be provided. These cookies don’t gather information about you for profiling or targeted marketing purposes. 

This category cannot be disabled using the cookies preference selection on this website. 

**Performance Cookies** – These cookies collect anonymous information about how visitors use our websites, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect personally identifiable information; the information collected is anonymous and is only used to improve the performance of our websites. 

These cookies are not used to target you with online advertising and without these cookies we cannot learn how our website is performing, and make relevant enhancements that could help improve your experience when using our online services. 

**Functionality Cookies** – These cookies allow our websites to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you're in) and tailor the website to provide enhanced features and content for you. These cookies can also be used to remember customisation changes that you may make (for example text size or fonts). They may also be used to provide services you asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect is anonymous and cannot be used to track your browsing activity on other websites. 

Without these cookies, a website cannot remember choices you've previously made or personalise your browsing experience. 

**Targeting Cookies** – These cookies gather information about your browsing habits. They remember that you've visited a website and share this information with other organisations such as advertisers. They do this in order to provide you with adverts that are more relevant to you and your interests. Although these cookies can track your visits to other websites, they don’t usually know who you are. 

Disabling these cookies will not stop online adverts from being displayed to you. However without these cookies, online adverts you encounter may be less relevant to you and your interests. 

**Setting your cookie preferences**

You can control how cookies are placed on your device either through the ‘Cookies’ link near the bottom of the page or from within your browser. 

**What happens to cookies that have been downloaded in the past?**

Once you've disabled a cookie category we'll stop using the associated cookies to gather any further information but we may still use information collected previously. You can delete existing cookies from your browser. 

**More information**

Information about cookies: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Internet Advertising Bureau: [Guide to online advertising and privacy](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

International Chamber of Commerce United Kingdom: ICC UK [cookie guide](http://www.international-chamber.co.uk/components/com_wordpress/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/icc_uk_cookie_guide.pdf)

All of the external sites you can reach through this website are here to help you. However, we must tell you that we accept no responsibility or liability for the content, accuracy or availability of any external site you may encounter. 

Back to top

###  How will we use the information we collect about you? 

We will store and process your information on the Barclays Group computers wherever located (including outside the European Economic Area (EEA)) and in any other medium. By "your information" we mean personal and financial information we:  
(a) obtain from you or from third parties and other organisations when you apply for an account or any other product or service for which you or they give to us at any other time; or  
(b) learn from the way you use and manage your account(s), from the transactions made, if any, such as the date, amount, currency and the name and type of supplier (e.g. supermarket services, medical services, retail services). 

By "Barclays Group" we mean subsidiaries of Barclays Bank PLC (as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985). We and other companies in the Barclays Group will use your information to manage your account(s), give you statements and provide our services, for assessment and analysis (including credit and/or behaviour scoring, market and product analysis), to identify and tackle fraud, money laundering and other crime, carry out regulatory checks and meet our obligations to any relevant regulatory authority, and to develop and improve our services to you and other customers and protect our interests. 

We and other members of the Barclays Group may use your information for marketing purposes. If you don't want us to tell you about other products and services, please write to us and supply us with your full name and address and details of any products or services you have with us. Please write to your normal point of contact, or your Relationship Manager. Alternatively, contact us. 

Back to top

###  Will we share your information with anyone else? 

We may share your information including how you manage your account or Site visit with other companies within the Barclays Group and/or to relevant third parties and as permitted by law including but not limited to the following: 

  * People who provide a service to us or are acting as our agents, on the understanding that they will keep the information confidential. 
  * Anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer all or any part of our business or assets, from whom we acquire any business or assets or who acquires substantially all of the assets of Barclays Bank PLC. 
  * Credit reference and fraud prevention agencies. 
  * We may also give out information about you if we have a duty to do so in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use or if the law allows us to do so. 

If we disclose your information to a service provider (a person, office or organisation) located in another country (including locations outside of the European Economic Area), we will take steps reasonably necessary to ensure that they apply the same levels of protection as we are required to apply to your information and to use your information only for the purpose of providing the service to us. By submitting your personal information you agree to this transfer. 

Back to top

###  How long will we keep your personal information on file? 

We will retain information about you after the closure of your account or service provision for as long as it is permitted for legal, regulatory, fraud prevention, business and financial crime purposes. 

Back to top

Under applicable data protection legislation you may be entitled, on payment of a fee, to a copy of the personal information you have provided. If any data is inaccurate it will be corrected without delay. Please inform your Relationship Manager or normal point of contact. 

###  Electronic communications 

Please remember that Internet communications are not secure unless the data being sent is encrypted. We cannot accept any responsibility for the unauthorised access by a third party and/or the corruption of data being sent by individuals to the Barclays Group. It is your responsibility to determine whether you need to encrypt your data before sending. 

Back to top

###  Intellectual Property 

The entire content of the Site is subject to copyright with all rights reserved and it may only be stored, held or used for your personal use only. You may not download (all or in part) for non-personal use or otherwise reproduce, transmit or modify the Site without our prior permission. However, you may print out part or all of the Site for your own personal use. These permissions are revocable by us at any time. Barclays is a registered trade mark owned by Barclays Bank PLC. You are granted a non-exclusive licence of those rights in order to view this site on a non-commercial basis only, revocable at any time. 

Back to top

###  Security 

It has always been our policy that if any of our clients are victims of unauthorised access to their accounts we will cover any resulting direct financial loss which the Client suffers provided that the Client has not breached our security procedures. 

You must ensure that viruses, trojans, worms or equivalent or similar items do not enter your computer system. We assume no responsibility for loss of whatever nature, howsoever arising, resulting from such viruses, trojans, worms or equivalent or similar items. 

For further information and advice on security, please click on Security. 

###  Calls 

We may record and monitor calls made or received by us to maintain high quality service standards, to check instructions, for your protection and ours, and for regulatory reasons. 

Back to top

###  Your Queries 

If you have any queries regarding privacy issues then please [email us](mailto:priv.acy@barclayswealth.com), or write to us at Barclays, Data Protection Officer, 1 Churchill Place, Risk – Level 16, Canary Wharf, London, United Kingdom E14 5HP. 

Back to top

###  External Links 

All of the external sites you can reach through Barclays Online are here to help you. However, we must tell you that we accept no responsibility or liability for the content, accuracy or availability of any external site you may encounter. 

Back to top
